Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and for those of you who have been following, this is the very
我是Catherine，对于一直关注我们的听众来说，这是
last episode of our 10-part series about giving a presentation in English.
我们关于用英语做演讲的十集系列节目的最后一集。
That's right. This is part 10 where we are going to receive questions from the audience.
没错。这是第十部分，我们将接受观众的提问。
So this is called a Q&A session or question and answer session. Let's take a listen to
所以这被称为问答环节。让我们来听一下
our dialogue. We'll be back in a moment.
我们的对话。我们马上回来。
Well everyone, I'm sure you'd like to join me in thanking Michael for what was a really
各位，我相信你们愿意和我一起感谢Michael，他做了一场非常
inspirational presentation. Sincere thanks, Michael. Now I'm sure many of you will be
鼓舞人心的演讲。衷心感谢，Michael。现在我相信你们很多人会
keen to ask some questions, so I'd like to open up a Q&A session. Please raise your hand
很想提问，所以我想开始问答环节。请举手
if you have any questions at all. Yes, Janice, go ahead.
如果有任何问题。好的，Janice，请讲。
Yes, thank you, Jonathan. I would just like to go back to the comment Mr. Ford made in
好的，谢谢，Jonathan。我想回到Ford先生提到的关于
regards to our competitors, particularly Orange. Now as you know, Orange has established themselves
我们竞争对手的评论，特别是Orange。如你所知，Orange已经确立了自己
as the market leader in the high-end laptop market. How does Mr. Ford expect to compete
在高端笔记本电脑市场的领导者地位。Ford先生打算如何与
with a company that has such a huge reputation and huge resources?
一个拥有如此巨大声誉和资源的公司竞争？
Well Janice, first of all, thanks for a very good question. I think you have hit the nail
好的Janice，首先，感谢你提出一个很好的问题。我认为你实际上
on the head actually. Orange are the global leaders precisely because of their size and
说到了点子上。Orange之所以是全球领导者，正是因为他们规模庞大、
power. But although we can't compete in terms of size, I do believe we hold an advantage
实力雄厚。但尽管我们在规模上无法竞争，我确实相信我们在
in terms of dedication to customer service. Yes, I admit this is a David and Goliath battle,
客户服务的投入方面拥有优势。是的，我承认这是一场大卫与歌利亚的战斗，
but don't forget who won that contest.
但别忘了谁赢得了那场比赛。
Mr. Ford, could you elaborate on actual technical details of the X420 a little more?
Ford先生，你能再详细说明一下X420的实际技术细节吗？
I'd love to, but I think we're a little pressed for time right now. However, Jonathan has
我很乐意，但我觉得我们现在时间有点紧。不过，乔纳森在
all the technical specs for you on the PowerPoint presentation, which you can look over in your
PowerPoint演示文稿里为你准备了所有技术规格，你可以抽空
own time.
自己看看。
Mr. Ford, one final question. Would you like to join me for a game of golf this Sunday?
福特先生，最后一个问题。这个周日您愿意和我一起打高尔夫吗？
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at some words on Language Takeaway.
好了，我们回来了。现在来看看“语言要点”中的一些单词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Well, at the beginning of today's dialogue, Jonathan said, I'm sure many of you will be
在今天的对话开头，乔纳森说：“我相信你们很多人都会
keen to ask some questions. What does this word keen mean?
很想问一些问题。”这个词“keen”是什么意思？
All right. So to be keen to do something, which basically means that you want to or
好的。“to be keen to do something”基本上意味着你想要或
would like to do something.
愿意做某事。
Right. Are you keen? Would you like to do it? Are you interested in doing it?
对。你“keen”吗？你想做吗？你有兴趣做吗？
Now, this is a very British form of addressing something, right?
这是一种非常英式的表达方式，对吧？
That's right. This is very British. We don't really say this as much in America, but you
没错。这非常英式。在美国我们不常这么说，但你
can. People will understand you. I would say, I'm sure many of you would like to ask some
可以用，别人会理解你。我会说：“我相信你们很多人都会想问一些
questions and so you could say that both ways.
问题”，两种说法都可以。
That's right. That's right. Okay. So many people want to ask questions and Jonathan
对，对。好的。所以很多人想问问题，乔纳森
said, so I'd like to open it up to a Q&A session. So the series of words here, to open it up
说：“所以我想开放问答环节。”这里的词组“to open it up
to a Q&A session. What does that mean?
to a Q&A session”是什么意思？
To open it up. It means the discussion. So he would like to invite people to ask questions.
“To open it up”指的是讨论。所以他希望邀请人们提问。
So I'd like to open it up for questions mean I would like to give you guys the opportunity
所以“我想开放提问”意思是我想给你们机会
to ask.
问一下。
So to open up a discussion or to open up a conversation, right?
所以，开启一个讨论或开启一段对话，对吧？
I would like to open this up to you guys.
我想把这个问题抛给你们。
Okay. Now, one of the audience members asked about another company, which is their competitors
好的。现在，一位观众问到了另一家公司，也就是他们的竞争对手，
and said that they have a huge reputation and huge resources, this competitor. So what
并说这个竞争对手有很高的声誉和巨大的资源。那么，
is this word reputation?
“reputation”这个词是什么意思？
Reputation is important. A person can have a reputation, but a company can also have
声誉很重要。一个人可以有声誉，一家公司也可以有
a reputation. Now, reputation means the way that other people talk about you. Okay. So
声誉。现在，声誉指的是别人如何谈论你。好的。所以
he has a good reputation means people say good things about him. Or the media like newspapers
他声誉好，意味着人们说他好话。或者媒体，比如报纸
and websites, they say good things about him. But if you have a bad reputation, it means
和网站，都说他好话。但如果你声誉不好，那就意味着
people are saying bad things about you.
人们在说你的坏话。
Right. Okay. So that pretty much sums it up a reputation, what other people say about
对。好的。这基本上总结了声誉——别人怎么谈论
you or how other people see you. So maybe if a company like this has a huge reputation,
你，或者别人怎么看你。所以，如果一家公司有很高的声誉，
it means that it's very well respected and people talk very good thing and people talk
那就意味着它非常受尊敬，人们说它好话，人们
well about this company.
对这家公司评价很好。
That's right.
没错。
Right. Now, another question came along and they wanted to know a little bit more about
对。现在，另一个问题来了，他们想多了解一些
the technical details of this product that they are introducing. And Mr. Ford said that,
关于他们正在推出的产品的技术细节。福特先生说，
you know what, right now we don't really have time, but I'm going to leave all the technical
你知道吗，现在我们没时间了，但我会把所有技术
specs on this PowerPoint presentation and you can look at it later.
规格留在PPT演示文稿里，你可以稍后查看。
Okay. So specs, this is something you'll hear very, very often, especially in technical
好的。所以“specs”这个词，你会非常非常频繁地听到，尤其是在技术领域，
areas, but it means specifications or details. So maybe I have a computer and I know it's
但它指的是规格或细节。比如我有一台电脑，我知道它是
an IBM computer, but I don't know the specs. I don't have the details. So that's something
一台IBM电脑，但我不知道它的规格。我没有具体细节。所以当你遇到问题或想更深入了解时，
that you would want to find out if you have a problem or you want to look into it more
这就是你需要弄清楚的东西。
closely. And so specs.
这就是“specs”的意思。
That's right. Okay. So these are the specs. Now, why don't we take a break? Let's take
没错。好的。这就是这些规格。现在，我们休息一下怎么样？让我们
a look at our dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
再看一遍我们的对话，一会儿回来。
Well everyone, I'm sure you'd like to join me in thanking Michael for what was a really
各位，我相信你们都想和我一起感谢迈克尔，他做了一场非常
inspirational presentation. Sincere thanks, Michael. Now I'm sure many of you will be
鼓舞人心的演讲。衷心感谢你，迈克尔。现在我相信你们很多人都会
keen to ask some questions. So I'd like to open up a Q and A session. Please raise your
急于提问。所以我想开始一个问答环节。请举手
hand if you have any questions at all. Yes, Janice, go ahead.
如果你有任何问题。好的，珍妮丝，请讲。
Yes. Thank you, Jonathan. I would just like to go back to the comment Mr. Ford made in
好的。谢谢你，乔纳森。我想回到福特先生刚才提到的关于
regards to our competitors, particularly Orange. Now, as you know, Orange has established themselves
我们竞争对手的评论，特别是Orange公司。如你所知，Orange已经确立了自己
as the market leader in the high-end laptop market. How does Mr. Ford expect to compete
在高端笔记本电脑市场的领导者地位。福特先生打算如何与一家
with a company that has such a huge reputation and huge resources?
拥有如此巨大声誉和资源的公司竞争？
Well Janice, first of all, thanks for a very good question. I think you have hit the nail
嗯，珍妮丝，首先，感谢你提出了一个非常好的问题。我认为你实际上
on the head, actually. Orange are the global leaders precisely because of their size and
说到了点子上。Orange确实是全球领导者，正是因为他们的规模和
power. But although we can't compete in terms of size, I do believe we hold an advantage
实力。但尽管我们在规模上无法竞争，我确实相信我们在
in terms of dedication to customer service. Yes, I admit this is a David and Goliath battle,
客户服务的投入方面拥有优势。是的，我承认这是一场大卫与歌利亚的较量，
but don't forget who won that contest.
但别忘了那场比赛谁赢了。
Mr. Ford, could you elaborate on extra technical details of the X420 a little more?
福特先生，您能再详细说明一下X420的额外技术细节吗？
I'd love to, but I think we're a little pressed for time right now. However, Jonathan has
我很乐意，但我觉得我们现在时间有点紧。不过，乔纳森有
all the technical specs for you on the PowerPoint presentation, which you can look over in your
所有技术规格都在PPT演示文稿里，您可以自己抽空
own time.
慢慢看。
Mr. Ford, one final question. Would you like to join me for a game of golf this Sunday?
福特先生，最后一个问题。您愿意这个周日和我一起打高尔夫吗？
Alright, we're back. So now let's take a look at some of those phrases on Fluency Builder.
好了，我们回来了。现在让我们看看“流利度构建器”中的一些短语。
The first phrase we have here is one that I really like and I use very often. It's,
我们这里的第一个短语是我非常喜欢并且经常用的。它是，
I think you have hit the nail on the head.
“我认为你说到点子上了。”
That's right. To hit the nail on the head. So this is a very common phrase, which basically
没错。“说到点子上”。这是一个很常见的短语，基本上
means I think you got it exactly right.
意思是“我认为你说得完全正确。”
Okay. So think about a nail that you're hammering something, you have a hammer in your hand.
好的。想象一下你在钉钉子，手里拿着锤子。
It's very easy to miss, but boom, when you hit it, hit the nail on the head, it means
很容易打偏，但“砰”的一声，当你打中时，打到钉子的头上，意思是
you have it exactly right.
你完全说对了。
That's right. So this was actually a response to one of the questions because it was a very
没错。这实际上是对其中一个问题的回应，因为那是个
good question and it had a valid point. So this is why Mr. Ford said you hit the nail
很好的问题，而且观点很有道理。所以福特先生才说“你说到
on the head. This is exactly right. I completely agree with you.
点子上了”。这完全正确。我完全同意你的看法。
After that though, we had this interesting phrase. He said, I admit this is a David and
在那之后，我们听到了一个有趣的短语。他说：“我承认这是一场大卫与
Goliath battle.
歌利亚之战。”
Okay. So now this is obviously, he's speaking metaphorically, right?
好的。显然，他是在打比方，对吧？
That's right. So David and Goliath, that's actually a story that we often talk about.
没错。大卫和歌利亚，这其实是我们经常谈论的一个故事。
It's a biblical story, so it comes from Christianity and David and Goliath fought, but David was
这是一个圣经故事，来自基督教。大卫和歌利亚战斗，但大卫
very, very small and Goliath was a monster. He was very big. And so everyone said Goliath
非常非常小，而歌利亚是个巨人，他非常高大。所以大家都说歌利亚
will win the fight, but David won the fight. And so this is an example or a story that
会赢，但大卫赢了。所以这是一个例子或故事，
people often use when they say, listen, it may be the case that you think the big giants
人们经常用它来说：听着，你可能认为大巨人
will win, but actually the small man or our small company will win.
会赢，但实际上小人物或我们的小公司会赢。
That's right. As you said, we many times make reference to this, even not in the biblical
没错。正如你所说，我们经常引用这个，即使不是从圣经
sense, but it's just the size. Maybe we're a small company, we're going to fight this
意义上讲，而只是指规模。也许我们是一家小公司，我们要和这家
big company. So we say it's a David and Goliath battle or even athletes, maybe two boxers.
大公司竞争。所以我们说这是一场大卫与歌利亚之战，甚至对运动员来说，比如两个拳击手。
One is bigger than the other. So they'll say it's a David and Goliath boxing match.
一个比另一个大。所以他们会说这是一场大卫与歌利亚的拳击赛。
That's right.
没错。
Okay. Now when we got the questions about the technical details of the computer, Mr.
好的。当有人问到电脑的技术细节时，福特
Ford said that we are a little bit pressed for time right now. That's why we can't really
先生说我们现在时间有点紧。这就是为什么我们不能真正
answer that question.
回答那个问题。
That's right. And so to be pressed for time means that you don't have a lot of time. You
没错。“时间紧”意味着你没有很多时间。你
are in a rush.
很匆忙。
That's right. So if you are pressed for time, you don't have too much time. You can't, you're
没错。所以如果你时间紧，你就没有太多时间。你基本上
in a hurry basically.
是在赶时间。
So I could say, Hey Marco, can you come here and look at this thing on my computer please?
所以我可以这样说：“嘿，马可，你能过来看看我电脑上的这个东西吗？”
I'm sorry. I'm a little bit pressed for time right now. I'll take a look at it in an hour.
“抱歉，我现在时间有点紧。我一小时后会看。”
Okay. So those are all of our phrases from Fluency Builder. Let's take another listen
好的。这些就是我们“流利度构建器”中的所有短语。让我们再听一遍
to our dialogue and we'll be right back.
对话，我们马上回来。
Hello everyone. I'm sure you'd like to join me in thanking Michael for what was a really
大家好。我相信你们都想和我一起感谢迈克尔，他做了一场非常
inspirational presentation. Sincere thanks Michael. Now I'm sure many of you will be
鼓舞人心的演讲。衷心感谢迈克尔。现在我相信你们很多人都会
keen to ask some questions. So I'd like to open up a Q and A session. Please raise your
很想问一些问题。所以我想开始问答环节。请举手
hand if you have any questions at all. Yes, Janice, go ahead.
如果有任何问题。好的，珍妮丝，请说。
Yes. Thank you, Jonathan. I would just like to go back to the comment Mr. Ford made in
好的。谢谢你，乔纳森。我想回到福特先生刚才提到的
regards to our competitors, particularly Orange. Now, as you know, Orange has established themselves
关于我们竞争对手的评论，特别是Orange。如你所知，Orange已经确立了自己
as the market leader in the high end laptop market. How does Mr. Ford expect to compete
在高端笔记本电脑市场的领导者地位。福特先生打算如何与
with a company that has such a huge reputation and huge resources?
一家拥有如此巨大声誉和资源的公司竞争？
Well Janice, first of all, thanks for a very good question. I think you have hit the nail
嗯，珍妮丝，首先，感谢你提出一个很好的问题。我认为你确实说到
on the head actually. Orange are the global leaders precisely because of their size and
点子上了。Orange之所以是全球领导者，正是因为他们的大小和
power. But although we can't compete in terms of size, I do believe we hold an advantage
实力。但尽管我们在规模上无法竞争，我确实相信我们在
in terms of dedication to customer service. Yes, I admit this is a David and Goliath battle,
客户服务的投入方面有优势。是的，我承认这是一场大卫与歌利亚之战，
but don't forget who won that contest. Mr. Ford, could you elaborate on actual technical
但别忘了谁赢了那场比赛。福特先生，您能再详细说明一下X420的实际
details of the X420 a little more? I'd love to, but I think we're a little pressed
技术细节吗？我很乐意，但我觉得我们现在时间有点
for time right now. However, Jonathan has all the technical specs for you on the PowerPoint
紧。不过，乔纳森有所有技术规格都在PPT演示文稿里，
presentation which you can look over in your own time.
您可以自己抽空慢慢看。
Mr. Ford, one final question. Would you like to join me for a game of golf this Sunday?
福特先生，最后一个问题。您愿意这个周日和我一起打高尔夫吗？
Alright so that was part 10 of our 10-part series about presentations. We took a look
好了，这是我们关于演讲的十集系列中的第十集。我们探讨了
at many different aspects where you can take it as an example as we talked about computers
许多不同的方面，你可以把它当作例子，就像我们讨论电脑
and marketing, but you can more or less have an idea of how a presentation should go and
和市场营销一样，但你可以大致了解演讲应该如何进行以及
the type of vocab you can use. That's right, and I think that this particular
可以使用哪些词汇。没错，我认为今天这个特定的
dialogue today was very, very useful because a lot of times you're going to have people
对话非常非常有用，因为很多时候会有人
asking you questions and filling in details, and so you can use some of these phrases to
问你问题并补充细节，所以你可以用这些短语来
help explain exactly what your presentation was about when people do have questions.
帮助解释你的演讲内容，当人们有问题时。
That's right. So we hope that you enjoyed this series and we would like to hear from
没错。所以我们希望你喜欢这个系列，如果你有其他关于
you if you have any other suggestions about a series of dialogues or a series of lessons
我们可以做的对话系列或课程系列的建议，我们很乐意听取
that we can do. We had one about a job interview, all the steps and everything, how a job interview
你的意见。我们之前有一个关于求职面试的系列，包括所有步骤和一切，求职面试
would go. We just had a series about presentations, so maybe you can give us some feedback or
会如何进行。我们刚刚完成了一个关于演讲的系列，所以也许你可以给我们一些反馈或
some ideas of what you would like to learn. Let us know. Our website is EnglishPod.com.
一些你想学习的想法。告诉我们。我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
We'll see you there. Alright, bye.
我们那里见。好了，再见。
Bye.
再见。